Let's look at a few examples factors we can use with this cross-sectional risk model.
我们看看横截面风险模型可以使用的几个示例因子
There are categorical factors such as the country in which
有一些类别因子 例如公司所在的国家
the company is based or the sector that it is a part of.
或者公司所属的行业
Intuitively, we can imagine that the country of
可以想象公司所在的国家
a company may affect its stock price movement in some way.
可能会以某种方式影响到公司的股价变化
For instance, if a country's government added or
例如 如果某个国家的政府
removed regulations that impacted only countries that
新颁布了或取消了仅影响
operated in that country then the impact would be
在此国家运营的公司的法规
concentrated on companies that are exposed to that country.
那么这种影响会集中在暴露于该国家的公司上
Similarly, it makes sense that
同理 公司所在行业
companies sector is a useful indicator about its stock price movements.
也可以作为很好的公司股价变化信号
For instance, if oil prices increased sharply,
例如 如果油价飙升了
we can imagine this having a positive impact
那么对大多数石油和天然气生产公司
on the stock price of most companies that operate in
会产生正面影响
the oil and gas production sector but have a negative impact on
但是对购买石油和天然气产品的公司
businesses that buy oil and gas products such as airlines or trucking companies.
会产生负面影响 例如航空或卡车运输公司
What you may notice about categorical variables such as country
你可能已经注意到了
or sector is that we can't sort categorical variables.
我们无法对国家或行业等类别变量进行排序
Sorting only makes sense if we have numerical data.
我们只能对数字数据进行排序
Recall that if we were to try using a time series risk model,
如果我们要使用时间序列风险模型
our first step would be to create
那么第一步需要创建一个理论投资组合
a theoretical portfolio whose daily returns represent the factor returns.
该投资组合的每日收益率代表因子收益率
But to construct the theoretical portfolio representing the factor,
但是要创建代表该因子的理论投资组合
we first need to sort the values so that
我们首先需要对值排序
we can divide them into separate quantile groups.
从而按百分比对它们分组
This isn't possible with categorical variables like a country or sector.
但是 国家或行业等类别变量不能这么操作
Let's talk about how we normally handle categorical variables.
我们来讨论下通常如何处理类别变量
You may have heard of dummy variables or one-hot encoding.
你可能听过虚拟变量或独热编码
If the country category has 12 unique countries for instance,
例如 如果国家类别有 12 个不同国家
then we could expand the single country variable into
那么我们可以将单个国家变量扩展成
12 separate variables each representing one country.
12 个单独的变量 每个代表一个国家
So, if a stock where in the USA,
如果股票在美国
it would have a value of one assigned to the USA
那么变量 USA 的值为 1
variable and zero for all other country variables.
所有其他国家变量的值为 0
When we think in terms of the factor model,
对于因子模型
the value of one or zero that is assigned to each country
分配给每个国家变量的值 1 或 0
variable is the factor exposure for that stock to that country.
表示该股票暴露于该国家的因子暴露度